翻译：sienna hodala 妮妮她姑 Sisley Gabrielle
■
翻译：考拉是S Hannah爱天津 拉面配卤蛋
时间轴：大喷子 Jessie
■
校对：阿飘
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉    总监：阿飘怒战八百米
■
天堂执法者
第四季 第七集
我还是觉得不太好
I'm still not comfortable with this.
史蒂夫  岛上谁不认识你和五零特遣队
Steve, everyone on this rock knows you and Five-O.
所以如果你们出现的话
So if you guys show up,
你们还没从前门进来
the clientele's gonna be out the back door
目标就已经从后门跑了
before you even step foot in the front,
但他们不认识我
but they don't know me.
-那我们换个地方吧  -不  不行
- Maybe we do a different location.  - No, no, no.
这家伙不想任何人知道他在赌场
This guy doesn't want anyone to know that he's in the casino,
所以这是唯一
so it's the only place
他不会带保镖的地方
where he's not gonna have security with him.
我监视过那里  我知道怎么进去
I've surveilled it; I know how to get in,
我也知道怎么出来  一举成功
I know how to get out. Boom.
如果你的身份被识破  怎么办
What if you get compromised?
我会随机应变
I'll improvise.
是你让我尽快回到正轨的  好吗
You're the one who told me to get back up on the horse, okay?
你说得没错
And you were right.
所以这次让我去做吧
So you're just gonna have to let me do this.
五零特遣队
干嘛  你要给我授权
What, are you deputizing me?
只是以防万一  好吗
Just in case, all right?
别担心  不会有事的
Don't worry, it's gonna be fine.
我能行的  好吗
I've got this covered, okay?
没事的
It's gonna be fine.
火奴鲁鲁  私人俱乐部
六点  派司拉赢
Six, pass line wins.
派司拉  又名花旗骰  一种赌博玩法
看来你不适合在赌桌对面下注呢
Betting against the table hasn't been working for you, huh?
也许换种玩法能赢钱哦
Maybe you can get lucky some other way.
我们是不是在哪见过  小姐
Haven't we met before, Miss?
你想做什么
What do you want?
佐藤陆在哪
Riku Sato, where is he?
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
五零特遣队
Five-O.
现在告诉我佐藤在哪里
Now where the hell is Sato?
瓦胡岛  玛卡普乌海滩
兄弟  有好位置吗
Hey, bro, any good sets out there?
在选呢
Picking up.
如果运气好  能冲个炫酷的浪
If we're lucky, we'll get swell.
煎饼好吃吗
你太了解我了
那是好事还是坏事
好事
还需要什么吗  恋爱男
Anything else, lover boy?
娜妮  你在我背后偷看吗
Nani, you reading over my shoulder?
只看到腻歪的部分
Only the dirty parts.
还要咖啡吗
More coffee?
结账吧  谢谢
Just the check, please.
已经有人给你付掉了
Oh, it's already taken care of.
柜台那儿的那位先生
Gentleman at the counter.
-谢谢  娜妮  -没事
- Thanks, Nani.  - Sure.
给我钱干吗
What's that for?
格罗弗队长
Well, Captain Grover,
开门见山  我出来混也不是一两天了
let's just say I've been around long enough to know that
有人埋单  必有所求
when someone pays for your meal they usually want something.
拜托
Come on.
别那么愤世嫉俗嘛
Are you really that cynical?
我们那里  警察总相互埋单
Where I'm from, cops do that for each other.
再说  我之前拿枪指着你
Besides, I figured it was the least I could do
就当是聊表歉意的小小心意吧
after pointing a shotgun in your face.
是啊  那次人质事件搞得大家都挺不愉快的
Yeah, well, that hostage crisis was rough on everyone.
我觉得双方都有责任  这么说才公平
I think it's fair to say that there was fault on both sides.
警督
Lieutenant,
我知道州长给了你们特权
I realize the governor gives you guys a free pass,
但老实说
but to be honest,
那天我在那里看到的你的所作所为
that behavior I saw out there in the field the other day,
足以令你和你的警察兄弟们
that's a surefire way to get yourself alienated
分道扬镳
from your brothers in blue.
我是说  如果哪天你需要后援时
I mean, i'd hate to see you in a situation
后援却没有出现  这太糟糕了
where you call for backup and it doesn't show.
我觉得  这些话你该跟麦格瑞特去说
I think you need to be having this conversation with McGarrett.
我不觉得
I don't think so.
我不想跟麦格瑞特谈
I'm not having this conversation with McGarrett.
麦格瑞特都不算一个真正的警察
McGarrett's not a real cop.
他不会像警察一样去思考
He doesn't think like a cop,
也不会像警察一样去处事
he doesn't act like a cop.
但是你...
You, on the other hand...
我查过了  你是个好警察
I did my homework; you're a good cop.
在度过了这么大的难关之后  重新回到警队
Got your badge back after going through a rough patch.
我知道那是什么感觉
I know what that's like.
祝你有美好一天  队长
Have a nice day, Captain.
来了
I'm coming
我说了来了
I said I'm coming!
来了  来了
All right, all right.
是个女孩  恭喜
玛丽  怎么...
Mary, what...
你该看看你的脸
You should see your face.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
这是谁的孩子
Who's baby is this?
我的
Mine.
不  不是吧
No, it's not.
她是我的孩子
She's mine.
-我领养了她  -你在说什么
- I adopted her.  - What are you talking about?
她怎么会是你的孩子
How could it be yours?
已经领养一段时间了
It's been in the works for a while,
但是我挑最后期限才带回来
but I kept in on the DL
以防某人会有意见
in case a certain someone was gonna be critical about it.
不敢相信
I don't believe it.
她多可爱啊
Isn't she cute?
我给她取了爸爸的名字
I named her after Dad.
-你给她取名为约翰  -不是  是琼
- Oh, you named her John? - No, Joan.
玛丽  我不是有意见
Mary, I don't want to be critical,
但是你自己的生活还没打理好
but you have difficulty managing your own life.
你要怎么多照顾一个婴儿
How you gonna look after the baby?
我都能照顾好一个九十岁的老头
I think I took care of a 90-year-old man pretty well.
只照顾了三周  而且还死了
For three weeks, and he died.
他自然死亡的  好吗
He died of natural causes, okay?
好吧
Okay.
你得把孩子还回去  玛丽
You got to give her back, Mary.
史蒂夫  我不能像台游戏机一样就把她还了
Steve, I can't return her like she's an Xbox.
她不是游戏机
She's not an Xbox.
她是一个小婴儿  好吗
She's a little baby person, okay,
你的下半辈子都得
and this is a responsibility you're gonna have
对她负责
for the rest of your life.
被你念得都不想当妈了
You're really killing my buzz being a new mom.
谢谢
Thanks.
是我  好
Yeah? Okay.
我马上来
I'm on the way.
我得走了  听着
I got to go. All right, listen,
等我回来了我们再谈
we'll talk about this when I get back.
拜拜
Bye.
兄弟  听我说  在我看来
Buddy, listen to me, the way I see it,
不是玛丽领养孩子  而是你
Mary didn't adopt a kid; you did.
因为这只是时间的问题
All right, 'cause it's only a matter of time
在这个可怜的小宝贝
before that poor, unfortunate child
凌晨三点嚷着要喝奶的时候
is looking for some suckling at 3:00 A.M.,
她肯定会被丢给你的
is gonna be looking to you.
-不  不会这么闹心的  -不会吗
-No, there's gonna be no suckling,  -No?
因为那孩子会被送回去
'Cause that baby is going back.
你打算送孩子回去  回哪  孤儿院吗
Oh, you're gonna send it back, what, to the orphanage?
跟那些没人要的孩子们呆在一起吗
With a bunch of other kids that nobody wants?
-什么  -行  没事  那想法不错
- What? - Yeah, no, it's a good idea.
我的意思说  这办法总比
I mean, it's probably a better idea
让你妹妹照顾要好一点
than leaving it with your sister.
等等  你好像不赞成这么做
Wait a minute, I thought you didn't approve?
我不赞成
I don't approve.
那你到底站在哪一边
Okay, whose side are you on then?
我站在孩子能得到关爱这一边
I'm on the side where the kid has a chance of being loved.
如果你觉得玛丽能够胜任
If you think Mary is capable of doing that,
那我会非常支持的
then I'm all for it, okay?
先生们  我们这有一位男性受害人
Gentlemen, what we have here is a male victim.
死因显然是多处刀伤所致
C.O.D. is quite evident based on the multiple stab wounds.
他很可能是在水里遇到袭击
He was most likely attacked in the water.
也许是几个人在争抢这块分界带的归属权
Maybe a couple of guys got territorial over this break,
接着情况就失控了
and then it got out of hand.
分析得很有道理  但应该不是
A reasonable theory, but highly unlikely.
受害者的手部没有明显的防御性伤痕
The victim's hands are noticeably free of defensive wounds,
这就说明袭击是突发且在死者意料之外
which suggests that the attack was sudden and unexpected.
好吧  身份确认了吗
Okay, do we get an ID?
正要去确认
I was just getting to that.
我刚询问了负责的这片区域的救生员
Just spoke to a lifeguard who patrols this area.
他说受害人是这里的常客
He said our vic's a regular,
无论是否有浪  每周一早上九点都会来
here every Monday 9:00 A.M., swell or no swell.
就是说他的行程可以预测
Okay, so predictable schedule,
他受到了近距离的攻击
he's hit up close and personal,
而且没有防御性伤痕
no defensive wounds.
受害人可能是被熟人所杀
Our victim could've been attacked by somebody who knew him.
受害人名叫布赖恩・卡彭特
Our victim has been identified as Bryan Carpenter.
挟持人质  毒品交易  盗窃
Pinches for assault, drug charges, grand larceny,
这家伙几年里犯的事可真多啊
guy's been in and out of trouble for years.
可能是仇家跟着他来到海边的
Looks like his troubles followed him out to sea.
卡哈拉  布赖恩・卡彭特的住宅
有被破门而入的迹象
Got signs of a break-in.
这里已经被人翻查过了
Place has been tossed.
安全
Clear.
恐怕他们已经找到想要的东西了
I wonder if they found what they were looking for.
那是什么
What is that?
排水管下面有东西
Something under this drain.
这可能就是他们在找的东西
This could be what they were looking for.
里面还有什么
There's something else in there.
-哦  天呐  -阿成  是什么
-Oh, my God.  -Chin, what is it?
受害人不叫布赖恩・卡彭特
Our victim wasn't Bryan Carpenter.
法医办公室
他的名字叫麦特・赫钦斯
His name is Matt Hutchins.
几年前我在警校
He was a cadet at the Police Academy
教关于执行搜查令的课程时
when I was teaching a class
他是一名学员
on executing search warrants a few years ago.
一般情况下我不会记得学生
Normally, I don't remember students,
但麦特问了很多很有见地的问题
but Matt asked a lot of really smart questions.
有一天  他下课后拦住了我
One day, he cornered me after class
问我这份工作到底是什么样的
and asked me what the job was really like.
这孩子想要有所建树
The kid wanted to make a difference,
但不知道能不能做得到
but wasn't even sure it was possible.
他长大的地方很乱
He grew up in a rough neighborhood,
到处是毒贩  黑帮
drug dealing, gangs.
当我问他"为什么要做警察"时
When I asked him, "Why be a cop?"
他说他只懂这个"游戏"的规则
he said that "The game" was the only thing he knew,
他的将来不是混黑道  就是混白道
and that he would end up on one side of it or the other.
他希望能选择正确的道路
He wanted to take the right path.
所以他当上了警察
So he became a cop.
可是麦特从没拿到过警徽
Well, Matt never got his badge.
他在突击搜查中被查到藏有海洛因
He was busted for heroin possession.
于是被开除出了警校
He got kicked out of the Academy.
我当时很遗憾
I was disappointed.
我是ATF的特别探员布莱克・肯尼迪
Special Agent Blake Kennedy, ATF.
烟酒枪械管理署
我刚接到一通电话
I just got a call?
我的手下怎么了
What happened to my guy?
什么  你的手下
Sorry. Your guy?
麦特・赫钦斯在为ATF
Matt, uh, Hutchins was working
执行一项长期卧底行动
a long-term undercover op for ATF.
我是他的联络人
I was his handler.
那么他从没被警校开除过
So he was never kicked out of the Academy.
开除  当然没有  那都是帮他做的掩护
Kicked out? Hell no. That was all part of his cover.
是什么行动
What was the op?
我们让他渗入一个走私枪支的团伙
We had him infiltrate a gang of gunrunners.
一条联系亚洲和美国本土的走私网
A network with ties to Asia and the mainland.
麦特的任务是确认团伙人员的身份
Matt's job was to ID the players
以及记下交易记录
and record transactions,
而我们正要针对这些人铲除这个走私网
and we were just about to drop the net on these guys.
再过几周  麦特就可以功成身退了
Another few weeks and Matt would've a career bust.
如果你的人已经那么深入的话
If you guys were that close,
我们就得假设一件事了...
we have to assume one thing...
麦特的掩护身份被识破了
Matt's cover was compromised.
他是怎么死的
How?
他在今天早上遭到了袭击
He was attacked this morning.
我们认为他是被人故意杀害的
We believe he was deliberately targeted.
在哪儿
Where?
玛卡普乌海滩
Baby Makapu'u Beach.
我们今天刚去过那儿
We were just there today.
有目击者称他每周一都会去那儿
A witness told us that he surfed there every Monday.
我每周一都会带着儿子去那儿
My son and I go there every Monday.
他不能暴露自己
Well, he couldn't break cover,
我相信  这是他守护你们的方式
but I'm sure that was his way of keeping an eye on you.
你们查出是谁干的吗
Do you know who did this?
我们认为是他在卧底行动中结识的人
We believe it had something to do with his undercover assignment.
他在调查那些人  他恨他们
Those people he was investigating, he hated them.
你俩多久交流一次
How often did you two speak?
几周一次
Every few weeks.
一通短信  或是几句电话里的寒暄
A text here, a quick phone call there.
每次都是用不同的号码
Always from a different number.
但是上一次
But the last time,
他的声音有些不一样...
his tone was different...
怎么说
How so?
我也说不上来
I don't know.
听上去他很开心
He sounded happy.
所以我就以为
So I was under the impression that
也许很快就要结束了
maybe it was coming to an end and...
他可能很快就能回来了
he'd be home soon.
我丈夫为这份工作献出了一切
My husband sacrificed everything for that job.
警督  你一定要抓到害死他的王八蛋
Lieutenant, you need to find the bastards who did this.
这是我们在查的人  J.C.戴克
This is the guy we're after, J.C. Dekker.
他早期在北海岸
He spent his wayward youth on the North Shore
靠走私冰毒出名
making a name for himself in the ice trade.
十年前  他把生意转移到了这里
Now, ten years ago, he moved his operation into town
还升级了业务
and he upgraded his clientele,
开始走私分销枪支
focusing primarily on weapons distribution.
这些人都是一开始就跟着他混的人
Guys right below him have been there since the first dollar.
每个人都是单独招募入伙
Everyone else has been recruited along the way.
看上去麦特还挺有自己的一套
Looks like Matt worked his way up the chain of command.
正如我所说  那是麦特的天赋
Well, like I said: That was Matt's talent.
他知道见什么人说什么话
He was able to talk the talk,
以此来赢得自己的地位
and that earned him respect.
如果需要的话
And when it came time,
他不惜使用武力
he wasn't afraid to use some muscle.
我刚把他送进去的时候
When I first sent him in,
还不知道是什么情况
we didn't know what to expect.
我们以为最多是一个六个月的行动
We thought it was a six-month op at most.
但是因为麦特获取的情报很详尽
But Matt's intel was so good,
我们很快发现这是一起大案子
we soon realized we were sitting on a major case.
好吧  麦特不在了
Right, now that Matt's gone,
抓住这些坏蛋的机会也没有了
so are the chances of taking these guys out.
所以我才选戴克
That's why I like Dekker for this.
动机  手段  机会
Motive, means, opportunity.
这些人呢  发生了什么
What about these guys? What happened to them?
行动中阵亡
KIA.
就算戴克这么厉害  他还是遇到了问题
As tight as Dekker's operation is, he has his problems.
过去几个月里
In the last few months,
这些人渣被抢劫了好几次
these dirtbags have been robbed a number of times
是由一个暂未查明身份的三人团伙所为
by a three-man crew we have yet to identify.
这些抢劫是怎么发生的
How were these robberies going down?
这不是街头随机发生的抢劫
It wasn't any street-level, crime-of-opportunity stuff.
这是计划周全的劫逃行动
I mean, we're talking well-coordinated hit-and-runs.
现金交易  他们会抢
Cash drops, they were there.
武器存货  他们也抢
Guns in storage, they were there.
也许戴克认为麦特出卖了他们
All right, well, maybe Dekker thought Matt was selling 'em out.
把信息泄露给劫匪  害死他的小弟们
Giving information to the guys who were ripping off his boys.
也或许戴克发现麦特是个警察
Or maybe Dekker figured out Matt was a cop.
不管哪种推论
I mean, either way,
戴克都至少有两个杀掉这孩子的动机
Dekker had at least two motives to kill this kid.
-我们需要该案件的所有资料  -好的
- We're gonna need everything on this case. - Yeah.
琳达  你能过来一下吗
Linda, can you come over here for a moment?
琳达・戴维斯
Linda Davies,
这是史蒂夫・麦格瑞特
this is Steve McGarrett,
丹尼・威廉姆斯警探
Detective Danny Williams.
-你好  -他们是五零特遣队的
- Hi. - They're with Five-O.
琳达负责誊写麦特的所有报告
Now, Linda transcribed all of Matt's reports.
她会把所有你们需要的给你们
She'll get you everything you need.
当然  这边请
Of course. Right this way.
资料全在这里了
This is everything.
戴维斯小姐  冒昧地问一句
Ms. Davies, do you mind if we ask you
你和麦特有多熟悉
how well did you know Matt?
我们其实没见过面
We actually never met.
过去四年里  我只能听到他的声音
I've listened to his voice for the past four years.
他的每一份报告都由我誊写
I transcribed every one of his reports.
所以我能分辨什么时候他过得好
So I could tell when he was having a good week
什么时候过得不好
and when, when it was bad.
最近的几个报告里他看起来如何
How did he sound in his last few reports?
有没有异常  他提到什么威胁了吗
Anything unusual? Did he mention any threats?
如果你是想问他的身份是否暴露
If you're asking me if his cover was blown,
我只能这么说
I can tell you this:
做卧底的时间越长
the longer you leave an undercover out there,
就越容易感到疲劳  压抑  大意
they get tired and depressed, sloppy.
接着开始犯错
They start making mistakes.
这话不该我来说  但是我真的觉得
It's not my place to say this, but I, I really think
几个月前就有足够的证据将他们缉拿归案
we had enough to take these guys down months ago.
你为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
这份工作我做了很久了
I've been working this job for a while now,
我见过这个部门在证据更少的情况抓人
and I've seen this department take people down for much less.
如果我们能按照以往的方式出牌
If we would have done what we normally do,
我不禁会去想
I-I just can't help but wonder
麦特也许还能活着
if Matt would still be alive.
你来说还是我来说
All right, are you gonna say it or am I?
我没打算说话
I'm not saying anything.
我还没准备好指点江山
I'm not ready to start pointing fingers.
那好  我来说
Okay, I'll say it.
如果ATF几个月前能进行逮捕
If the ATF could have made an arrest months ago,
他们为什么不这样做
why didn't they?
将麦特留作卧底超过预定期限
Keeping Matt out there past his sell-by date
会暴露他的身份
could have compromised his cover.
要瓦解这样一个组织
Dismantling an operation like this,
并没有想象中那么简单
it is not as easy as it sounds.
想一想麦特  好吗
Think about Matt, all right?
这个人  也许他厌倦了
This guy, maybe he, uh, maybe he got tired,
也许他想家了  也许哪里疏忽了
maybe he missed his family, maybe somewhere he slipped up.
也许他疏忽了
Maybe he slipped up,
又或许是肯尼迪把他留在那里太久了
and maybe Kennedy kept Matt out there too long
因为他只在乎破案
because he cared more about making his case
不在乎手下的性命
than he did about looking after his boy.
也许  但是就像我说的
Maybe, but like I said,
在掌握有力的证据之前
I am not ready for pointing fingers
我是不会乱指江山的
until we have something that is real, okay?
我来告诉你什么有力
I'll tell you what's real:
J.C. 戴克  而且我告诉你
J.C. Dekker. And let me tell you something else.
一旦他有一秒怀疑
If he suspected for one second
麦特是警察  他都会解决了他
that Matt was a cop, he would take care of business.
我同意
I agree.
但是现在去打草惊蛇不是好主意
But to go rattle that cage right now is a terrible idea
因为我们可能坏了ATF整整三年的行动
because we could blow the ATF's entire three-year operation.
所以我们小心处理
So we'll tread lightly.
现在能听我说话了吗
Got your attention now or what?!
喂喂喂  说好的"小心处理"呢
Hey, hey, hey, what happened to "Tread lightly," Huh?
我给你三秒钟让你把手从我喉咙拿开
I'm giving you three seconds to get your hands off my throat.
不然呢
Or what?
你穿黑衣的女友还好吗
How's your girlfriend look in black?
坐下
Sit.
现在你听仔细了
Now listen to me very carefully:
你不准乱说话
You're done mouthing off.
从现在开始我问你的问题
I'm gonna ask the questions from now on.
你只需点头回答是或不是
You're just gonna nod yes or no.
布赖恩・卡彭特  你认识他吗
Bryan Carpenter, do you know him?
这动作算不上是或不是
That's not technically a yes or a no.
我就当你说是
I'm gonna take it as a yes.
顺便假设这是你的杰作
I'm also gonna assume that you did this.
出什么事了
What happened?
今天早上  你在哪里
This morning, where were you?
服从国家对我身体主权的
Complying with the state's unconstitutional invasion
违宪侵入
of my physical sovereignty.
什么玩意
Come again?
我的假释官让我去验尿
I was peeing in a cup for my P.O.
你可以问他
You can ask him.
好吧  这也不能证明你没有下令杀他
Okay, well, that still doesn't mean you didn't order the hit.
我为什么要杀他  布赖恩是我的朋友
Why would I do that? Bryan was my friend.
暂时假设你在说实话
Let's assume that you're telling the truth again for two seconds.
为什么会有人想要杀他
Why would somebody want to kill him?
我不知道
I have no idea.
而且你为什么会在乎我的人
And why do you care about one of mines anyway?
难道你现在不应该
Shouldn't you be celebrating
在甜甜圈店或者哪儿庆祝吗
at a donut shop or something right now?
听起来不错
That sounds excellent.
起来
Get up.
接下来这几天  你给我什么都别做
Now here's your itinerary for the next couple of days: nothing.
你不能离开这里  明白吗
You don't move from here, you understand?
火奴鲁鲁警局会在这里看着你
HPD's gonna sit on your place
直到我们破案
until we straighten this out.
如果我知道你离开
If I hear that you leave,
就算是去图书馆拿藏书
even to take your library books back,
威廉姆斯警探和我  我们会再来
Detective Williams and I, we're gonna come back
下次我俩就没这么有礼貌了
and we're not gonna be as courteous next time.
他还真是不动声色
Well, that was very subtle.
我肯定他正在给杀麦特那人打电话
I'm sure he's calling whoever killed Matt right now
告诉他们要低调
and telling 'em to lay low.
你在说什么  他没下令实施那次袭击
What are you talking? He didn't order the hit.
你没看到他脸上的表情吗
Did you see the look on his face?
他什么也不知道
He didn't know anything.
好吧  如果是这样
Okay, well, if that's the case,
那我们就得考虑
then we have to consider
麦特手脚不干净的可能性  好吗
the possibility that Matt was dirty, okay?
-不干净  -是的  不干净  好吗
- Dirty. - Yes, dirty, okay?
如果他在向那帮人售卖信息
If he was selling information to the crew
让戴克遭殃  而他自己却溜之大吉
that ripped off Dekker and he slipped off somewhere,
这可能会给他惹来杀身之祸
it would've gotten him killed.
丹尼  麦特是个警察
Danny, Matt was a cop.
我知道他是个警察  好吗
I know he was a cop, okay?
我在新泽西的时候认识不少人
I knew plenty of guys back in New Jersey
他们做卧底的时间太久了
that were undercover for so long,
最终陷入深渊
they ended up slipping;
他们不知道界线在哪里
they didn't know what the line was.
等等  等一下
Just-Just wait. Just wait.
是的  玛丽
Yes, Mary?
等等  什么
Wait-- what?!
开始了
And so it begins.
沙门氏菌
Salmonella?
真的还假的
Really?
我不应该在飞机上吃那个鸡蛋沙拉
I shouldn't have eaten that egg salad on the plane.
是啊
Yeah.
玛丽  这正是我们之前谈论过的情况
Mary, this is exactly what we were talking about before.
史蒂夫  坏掉的鸡蛋和我抚养孩子的技能
Steve, bad eggs have nothing to do
没有任何关系  好吗
with my parenting skills, okay?
我能做一个好妈妈
I could be a good mother,
只是不是现在而已
just not right now.
我真的需要你帮我照看一下琼
I really need you to watch Joan for me
因为我得在这儿过夜
'cause I have to stay here overnight.
不不不  我做不到
No! No, no, no! I can't do that.
史蒂夫  你必须这么做
Steve, you have to.
玛丽  不行  玛丽...
Mary, no, Mary...
我不知道还能找谁
I don't have anybody else to call!
-我得在这儿过...-玛丽
- I have to stay here over...  - Mary.
我现在正忙着
I'm in the middle, I'm in the middle
调查一宗凶杀案
of a homicide investigation.
好吧
Okay.
那我就打给儿童保护机构好了
I'll just call Child Protective Services.
然后琼就只能被安置在
And Joan will have to be placed
某个寄养家庭一阵子了
with a foster care family for a while.
我只希望这样的创伤不会
I just hope that the trauma doesn't
对她的认知发育有什么影响
affect her cognitive development.
认知  你都不知道这个词是什么意思
Cognitive? You don't even know what that word means.
你这个舅舅糟透了
You're a horrible uncle,
你知道吗
you know that?
很好笑吗
This funny to you?
当然了
Yeah!
那你笑完了之后
So when you're through amusing yourself,
帮我给她擦干净然后换尿布  拜托了
I need you to wipe down and change her pad, please.
我才不要  我早就不做奶爸了  你知道的
Not at all. I'm retired, you see.
而且看史蒂夫舅舅换尿布
And it's gonna be way too entertaining
实在是太有趣了  加油哦
to see Uncle Steve on diaper duty. So go ahead.
你胸口怎么"戴"了个孩子
Hey, why is there a baby attached to your chest?
是玛丽的
Oh, uh, Mary.
哦  不说了  祝你好运
Ah. Say no more. Mazel tov.
-谢了  -总之  我找到我们在
-Thanks.  - Anyway, I was able to track down
麦特家发现的那个钥匙的制造商了
the manufacturer of the key we found at Matt's house.
-好样的  -能追查到是他们卖给
- Oh, good. - It traces back to a set of locks
火奴鲁鲁动物园的一组锁
that they sold to Honolulu Zoo.
让我来看看
Oh, let me see that.
事实上  你知道吗  给你  就一会儿
Actually, you know what? Here, just for a second.
-什么  -小心点
- What?  - OK? Careful.
好的
Yeah, yeah.
好了  丹尼  我们走
Okay, Danny, let's go.
-等等  -如果她饿了的话
- Wait.  - If she gets hungry,
奶瓶在这儿  明白吧  我们走
bottle in here. You got it? Let's go.
等等  我怎么会知道她饿没饿
Wait-- how am I supposed to know if she's hungry?
你会知道的  相信我  你会的
Oh, you'll know. Trust me, you'll know.
佐藤
Sato?
我不认识叫佐藤的人
I don't know any Sato.
你知道吗  对一个爱赌博的人来说
You know for somebody who likes to gamble,
你的"扑克脸"可装的不怎么样
you don't have a very good poker face.
你的名字叫黑田秀明
Your name is Hideaki Kuroda.
你帮佐藤洗钱
You're Sato's moneyman.
你有一个妻子
You have a wife.
两个孩子
You have two children.
萝西和金
Rosie and Kin.
萝西在钢琴上很有天赋
Now, Rosie, she's very talented at the piano.
而金  他的数学很好
And Kin, well, he aced math,
但他需要一个科学家教  对吗
but he needs a science tutor. Right?
还有  你刚买了
Oh, and you just brought, um,
一辆崭新的跑车
a brand-new sports car.
给你的情妇
For your mistress.
目前为止  都说对了吧
So far, so good?
我还知道
I also know
你想脱离佐藤
that you want out of Sato's crew.
但你不能  因为你一直都在
But you can't because you've been gambling
用你老板的钱赌博
with your boss' money.
而且你一直在输钱
And you've been losing.
你想要掩盖这件事
Trying to cover it up,
把钱挪来挪去  拆东墙补西墙
moving the money around from place to place.
但这个漏洞
But that hole?
漏洞只是不断变大
Yeah, that hole just keeps getting deeper.
越来越大
And deeper.
既然我都知道了这些
Now if I know this,
那么佐藤发现这一切
Then really it's only a matter of time
只是时间问题
before Sato figures it out.
而且当他得知他拿不回钱
And when he realizes that he can't get his money back
是因为你把它们输光了
because you lost it
输在赌桌和赌马上
at blackjack and craps, and roulette and horses,
他会尽他所能  让你不得好死
he is gonna hurt you in the worst way that he can.
现在  我们能帮你
Now, we can help you,
秀明先生  但你必须先告诉我
Mr. Kuroda, but you first you got to tell me
佐藤在哪里
where I can find Sato.
你跟佐藤有什么过节
What business do you have with Sato?
我对佐藤一点兴趣都没有
I don't give a damn about Sato.
我只想问他
I just want to ask him
亚当・西村在哪里
where I can find Adam Noshimuri.
火奴鲁鲁动物园
在这儿  就是这些储物柜
There it is. There are the lockers.
B-24柜
B-24.
你还觉得麦特是清白的吗
You still think Matt's not dirty?
五零特遣队总部
我们找到了超过十万美元的现金
Okay. We got over a $100,000 cash.
解释给我听听  一个卧底警察
Explain to me how is it that
是怎么拿到这么多钱的
an undercover cop has this kind of money?
无法解释
I can't.
我没办法解释
Okay? I can't.
但这并不代表他手脚不干净
But that doesn't make him dirty.
史蒂夫  他把那个储物柜的钥匙
Steve, he had the key to that locker
藏在了浴室的出水口
hidden in a shower drain.
他不想任何人
He did not want anyone
发现这些现金  为什么
to see this cash-- why?
也许他被收买
Maybe he was getting paid
提供内幕消息
for inside information by the guys
给那些抢劫戴克的人
that were ripping off Dekker.
如果他是一个为了抓到戴克
That's a big maybe for a guy who put his wife
三年来把自己妻子和儿子的生命放在次位的人
and his son's lives on the backburner
这才有可能发生
for three years to take Dekker down.
千万别介意这股味道
Don't mind the smell.
哦  好吧  我懂了
Ooh! Yeah, I know.
豌豆糊
Strained peas.
还只消化了一半
Only partially digested.
给你  你能不能...
Here, could you, uh...?
-小宝贝  -谢谢
- Hey, hi. - Thanks.
你身上除了宝宝的呕吐物
Did you, uh, get anything
没再有别的吧
besides baby puke?
是啊  呵呵
Yeah. Funny.
我查了麦特和他老婆的信用卡记录
I ran the credit histories on Matt and his wife.
毫无异常  他们过得本本分分
Nothing unusual-- they live paycheck to paycheck
和岛上最诚实努力的好公仆无异
just like most honest hard-working civil servants on the island.
你能专注点么
Can we focus over here?
你们查了财务状况  没有异常
Yeah, you ran the finances, no surprises.
挺好  还有什么消息
Good, what else we got?
我查看了麦特的手机
I dumped Matt's phone.
唯一值得注意的的是
The only thing of note
他上周给当地房地产中介
was a series of phone calls
打了几个电话
to a local real estate agent all in the last week.
她叫切丽・特瑞顿
Name of Cherie Tranton.
房地产中介
Real estate agent?
你觉得奇怪吗
That seem strange to you?
也许是他房租涨价了
Maybe the lease is up on, uh, on his place.
对呀  也有可能他打算买房子
Ah, yeah, or maybe he was looking to buy some property
来洗黑钱
and launder some of this cash.
我去问问肯尼迪探员
I'll check in with Agent Kennedy.
看看他是不是知道钱
See if he knows anything about the money
或是房地产中介的事儿
or the real estate agent.
阿成  先等等
You know what, Chin? Hold off on that for now.
咱们先看看麦特的报告
Let's take a look at Matt's field reports first.
我现在还不想把ATF的人卷进来
I want to keep ATF out of the loop for now.
肯尼迪那儿有麦特的所有情报
Well, Kennedy had all the same intel Matt did. You know?
我明白了
Oh, I see.
所以我觉得是麦特有问题
So I'm crazy, my-my theory is nuts
这个推测太离谱了
thinking that Matt went bad,
而你的新推测是
but your new amazing idea
麦特的联络人才是
is Matt's handler was the one
把消息泄露给袭击戴克的人
giving information to the guys that ripped off Dekker.
我只是说有这个可能  好不好
Well, I'm just saying it's possible, okay?
咱们都听到肯尼迪的誊写员怎么说的了
We all heard what Kennedy's transcriber said.
肯尼迪原本可以在几周前就可以
Kennedy could've pulled Matt out
让麦特撤离  结束这个案子的
and taken the case down weeks ago.
这也就能解释为什么肯尼迪
That would explain why Kennedy kept Matt
-这么长时间都不让麦特撤离了  -是的
- out in the field so long. - Right.
所以咱们还得仔细看看记录
So let's just take a closer look at the transcripts.
看看是不是漏掉了什么  好吗
See if we're missing anything. All right?
-这是在搞什么  -轮到你了
- What are we doing? - It's your turn.
轮到我干什么了
My turn for what?
咱们可是个团队啊
We're a team.
丹尼  每个人都得十一分投入
Danny, everybody's got to put in 110%.
看看  这就是十一分的投入
Look at this-- that's 110% right there.
我和阿成去和戴克谈谈
Chin and I, we're gonna go talk to Dekker
看看他能不能解释下这些钱
see if he can shed some light on this cash.
与此同时  当你看孩子的时候
In the meantime, while you're on babysitting duty,
再去查查这个房地产中介
run background on this real estate agent.
查查戴克的团伙
See if there's any connection
和切丽・特瑞顿有没有什么关系
between Dekker's crew and Cherie Tranton.
尽量别让宝宝的口水流到物证上
And try not to let her drool on the evidence.
咱们还有用呢
We're gonna need it.
小孩儿挺聪明啊  我有个想法
Smart kid. Uh, I got an idea.
要不然我为团队身先士卒
Uh, why don't I step up for the team and,
我和阿成去
uh, Chin and I will go out.
你留下来  打打电话  处理一下
You stay here, make those calls, and deal with, uh,
你这脏兮兮的侄女
your soiled niece here?
赶快给她换尿布
Change her soon.
你知道么  否则她会起疹子的
You understand? Or she gets a rash.
是么
Oh, does she?
尿布在史蒂夫的办公室里
Diaper bag's in Steve's office.
奶瓶在冰箱里
Bottles are in the fridge.
你会用得上的
You're gonna need that.
为什么这个会在
Why was this in a storage locker
你死去的朋友的储物柜里
belonging to your dead friend?
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
这儿有十万美金
There's a hundred grand in there.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
因为这是我给他的
'Cause I gave it to him.
布赖恩向我借钱
Bryan asked me for a loan.
说周末就能还给我
Said he'd get it back to me by the weekend.
等等  一个人找你借十万美金
Wait a minute-- a guy asks you for a hundred thousand dollars
你就这么随随便便借了
and you just give it to him?
是的  我相信我的朋友
Yeah, I trust my friends.
他要这些钱做什么
What he want the money for?
老兄  我从不细问
I don't ask for details, man.
你不能为了我不知道的事儿难为我
What I don't know won't put me in a box.
如果你没完没了
Now if you're done harassing me,
我去和警卫吃点小鱼玉米卷
I'm gonna get some fish tacos with my police escort.
如果麦特没偷这些钱
If Matt didn't steal that money...
这些钱就无法证明
Yeah, it throws some cold water
他不干净  戴克
on the theory that he was dirty. Hey, Dekker?
除非把钱拿回来  否则我没什么可说的
I'm done talking until I get my money back.
你是指这些给孤寡基金会的捐款吗
Oh, you mean this donation to the Widows and Orphans Fund?
你可真大方
That's very generous of you.
要不然你跟我们讲讲
Now, listen, why don't you tell me about this crew
那些抢劫你的人  他们是谁
that's been ripping you off-- who are they?
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
那些袭击你的人
Those guys that have been hitting you
很有可能就是杀了你朋友的人
are probably the guys that killed your friend.
那么我衷心的希望你能抓住他们
Well, then I sincerely hope you catch them.
好吧  听我说
Okay, listen to me.
我知道你最近经济上出了问题
I know you've been taking some big financial hits lately.
我想帮你一把
Okay? So I want to do you a favor.
我会增加警卫巡逻
I'm going to extend our police presence.
你和你身边的每一个人
You and everybody in your life
都会由火奴鲁鲁警局24小时全方位保护
is gonna be protected by HPD 24-seven.
确保你们的安全
Just to make sure you feel safe.
我们会日夜坚守
We're gonna have eyes on you day and night.
祝你进出口生意兴隆
Yeah, good luck in the import and export biz.
好好吃玉米卷吧
Enjoy your tacos.
等一下
Wait.
我知道些事  有可能对你们有用
I got something that might help.
这是一个室内的监视录像
This is an in-house surveillance video
记录了一个当地帮派被另一拨团伙突击
from a local gang getting ripped off by another crew.
箱子里是什么东西
What's in the crates?
枪支  毒品  还有一些派对套餐
Guns, drugs and other party favors.
我对那些戴面罩的人比较有兴趣
I'm more interested in the guys behind the masks.
有没有什么办法能查他们的身份  查理
Is there any way we can ID these guys,Charlie?
总会有办法的
There's always a way.
我有发现了就打给你
I'll call you when I got something.
好的  谢了  哥们
All right, thanks, buddy.
对了  查理
Hey, Charlie?
你回来真是太好了
It's good to have you back.
很久很久以前有个非常英俊的王子
Once upon a time there was a very handsome prince.
而且呢  这个英俊的王子
And this, uh, handsome prince
有匹漂亮的黑马
had a very beautiful black stallion.
王国中的所有人
And this black stallion was, uh, was admired
都对这匹马称赞有加
by everybody in the kingdom.
它跑得最快而且姿态优美
He was the fastest and fairest stallion in the land,
马力大概有528匹  反正是匹好马
about 528 horsepower, very nice stallion, anyway.
有一天
Uh, one day, uh,
英俊的王子...
this incredibly handsome prince...
是吧  他瞎了  我告诉你
Yeah, he was, he was out of sight, let me tell you.
他和一个很刻薄的食人怪搭档
He was partnered up with a mean ogre.
奇丑无比而且全身长满毛的食人怪
A disgusting, hairy ogre.
真算不上是天造之和
It was not a match made in heaven.
他们时不时会一起去宰几头龙
They would slay dragons together from time to time.
而且他们总在吵架  当然
And they'd argue all the time and, of course,
聪明的王子殿下总能  总能吵赢
the brilliant charming prince would-would win those arguments
因为食人怪是个笨蛋
because the ogre was a dope.
尽管他们有过这些战绩
Despite their, uh, victories,
但他们之间总是有着若隐若现的矛盾
there was a dark cloud that loomed.
因为...
Because...
那个笨蛋食人怪
the dopey ogre coveted
对王子的好马垂涎已久
the handsome prince's stallion, okay?
他是个非常贪婪自私的食人怪
And he was a very greedy, selfish ogre
控制欲还很强
with-with major control issues.
从不让英俊的王子殿下骑自己的马
And he would never let the handsome prince ride his own stallion.
等等  我们得先接个电话
Hold on, we're gonna pick this up in a second.
很好  房地产中介打来了
Oh good, it's the real estate agent.
您好
Hello.
是的  我是
Yes, yes it is.
那太好了
Uh, that's perfect.
我可以在那里跟你见面
I can, uh, I can meet you there.
地址是什么
What's, uh, what's the address?
真快啊
That was fast.
得补偿错过的时间啊  来看看
Making up for lost time. Check it out.
我截取到了其中一人的清晰图像
I got a clean screen capture on one of your guys.
我们可以用来估计身高
We can estimate height,
体重  鞋码
weight, shoe size.
如果据此在火奴鲁鲁警局数据库里搜索
If we run those traits through the HPD arrest database?
我们就可以对上号
We're gonna get dozens of matches
-并找到很多嫌疑人  -但是
- and then lots of possible suspects. - But...
如果我们测量瞳距的话
if we measure pupillary distance,
这个人的瞳距是63.2毫米
which in this case is 63.2 millimeters,
然后结合其他线索
and we combine it with all of the other traits,
就能有效缩小搜索范围
it narrows the field considerably.
你好啊  乔伊・提勒曼
Aloha, Joey Tillman.
看看他做过什么  抢劫  持枪
Okay, what do we got? Robbery, guns,
故意伤人  屡次抢劫  就是他了
assault, more robbery. This has to be our guy.
特警队在来的路上了
You know, SWAT's on its way.
也许没必要问这个
Maybe I don't need to ask this,
不过我们要不要等等他们
but should we wait?
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
掩护
Cover!
看来有三名射手
Looks like we got three shooters.
这些人是靠走私武器谋生的
These guy move weapons for a living.
肯定从头武装到牙齿
They're gonna be armed to the teeth.
我们得等后援
We're gonna need more guns.
你们应该等特警队来了再行动的
You should've waited for SWAT.
你真的打算现在讨论这个问题吗
You really want to do this now?
停火
Hold fire!
这里是火奴鲁鲁警局特警队
This is HPD SWAT!
放下武器  出来投降
Drop your weapons and come out.
你们已经被包围
You are outnumbered.
这是唯一一次警告
This is your one warning.
是提勒曼
That's Tillman.
挪开
Move it.
安全
Clear!
-安全  -伙计
- Clear! - Hey, yo.
来看看这个
You'll want to come take a look at this.
跟监控录像里的板条箱是一样的
Same crates we saw in the surveillance videos.
他们肯定就是抢了戴克的那伙人
These have got to be the guys that've been ripping off Dekker.
我们马上发通缉令吧
All right, let's get an alert out right away.
我记得你说过有三个射手
I thought you said there were three shooters.
确实是  第三个人肯定从后面偷溜了
There were. Third guy must've slipped out the back.
他是从后面偷溜的啊
Oh, he slipped out the back.
还真是干得漂亮啊  少校
Well, that's exemplary work, Commander.
史蒂夫
Steve.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
伤口是在后脑
Entry wound's in the back of the head.
这些人不是我们杀的
We didn't kill these guys.
是那第三个射手干的
The third shooter did.
那个在你眼皮底下溜走的家伙吗
Oh, you mean the guy that escaped on your watch?
在我的眼皮底下
On my watch?
交火的时候你可就在我旁边
You were standing right next to me when this went down.
这事本来不会发生
See, it wouldn't have gone down
如果你们稍微再等一等
if you just waited a little bit
让特警队来处理的话
and let SWAT do its job.
不过  就如我刚才所说
But, hey, like I said,
干得漂亮啊  上校
exemplary work, Commander.
他为什么要杀自己的人呢
So why does he shoot his own guys?
可能是想收拾掉所有走漏风声的人吧
Well, maybe he's tying up loose ends.
而这也可能也是谋杀麦特的动机
Which could be the same motive for killing Matt.
这第三个射手也许知道了
Maybe this third shooter knew
麦特快查到所有参与作案的人了
that Matt was getting close to the crew.
我们得知道  麦特要这些钱来做什么
We need to work out what Matt wanted that money for.
全新建筑
All new construction,
刚换上的新毛毯
brand-new carpeting,
特别设计的石英工作台
engineered quartz countertops.
而且这附近还有个很棒的学校小区
And there's a great school district
等你的小女孩长大了就正好合适
for your little girl, when she's ready.
不  谢谢你的好意
Oh, no, that's, uh... that's very nice.
她其实
She's, uh... she's actually
是我朋友的孩子  我只是临时照看她
a friend of mine's. I'm just babysitting.
我  我还单身
I'm, uh... I'm single.
天  好吧
Oh, my. Well...
能认识这么一个有爱心的人真好
So refreshing to meet somebody who's so... giving.
你肯定是个很热心的人
You must be a very warm person.
你还非常结实
And you're so fit.
谢谢称赞
Oh, thank you very much.
我就是特别欣赏把裤子穿得好看的男人
I just appreciate a man who can wear a pair of pants.
好吧  这房子设计很不错
Okay. Well... Now, this condo's got a great layout.
尽管只有一间卧室
Although... there's only one bedroom.
眨眼
Wink.
看  她说眨眨眼
Look at that. She said "Wink, wink,"
然后她就眨眼了
and then she winked.
-告诉我  -什么
- So tell me... - Huh?
是什么风
...what winds of fortune
把你这只小船吹来我这里来的
have blown your little ship into my harbor?
是麦特・赫钦斯
Oh, um... Matt Hutchins,
向我推荐了你的
actually recommended you.
赫钦斯先生
Mr. Hutchins!
他为你租下了这间公寓
Oh, did he rent the apartment for you?
是的
Yes, he did.
我不得不说
I have to say,
这种情况我还是第一次碰到
this was a first for me.
我见过很多人只是来看看
I mean, I have people who come and want to window shop,
但从没有人到这来  就租一天
but I've never had someone want to rent a condo for just one day.
是啊  就租一天
Well, uh, yeah, one day.
我们只需要一天就够了
That's all we need it for.
就今天  所以我们来了
Today's that day, so here we are.
是明天  小笨蛋
Tomorrow, silly.
对  对  是明天
Tomorrow, yes, of course.
我的意思就是明天
Tomorrow's that day, that's what I meant.
你知道  对这一千块
You know, for $1,000,
你们两个肯定有精心设计的安排
you boys must have something scintillating planned,
所以你最好把切丽的号码存着
so you better keep Cherie's number in your phone.
房东协会可不喜欢我们这种小交易
Homeowner's association doesn't like little side deals like this,
所以这是我们两个人的小秘密  知道吗
so it's our little secret, okay?
当然  切丽  你还真淘气
All right. Cherie, you're very naughty.
亲爱的  你猜不透我的
Honey... you have no idea.
你一定爱这里的风景
You are gonna love this view.
太棒了
Wow, very nice.
史蒂夫
Hey, Steve.
我有东西要让你看  快过来
Something you gotta see. Come down here.
看起来麦特在监视那个
It seems like Matt was running surveillance
我们发现了钱的柜子
on the lockers where we found the money.
我说  如果你要让宝宝晒到太阳
You know what, if you're gonna hold the baby in the sun, okay,
你跟我说  我会给她戴上太阳帽的
just ask me and I'll put a sunhat on her.
但现在的问题是
You know what, though? The question is,
为什么他要监视那个柜子
why would he be doing surveillance on the lockers?
麦特记录了所有戴克的武器交易
Okay, Matt recorded all the times and dates
时间和地点  是不是
of Dekker's weapons transactions. Right?
那帮抢劫戴克的人也有所有信息
The crew that was ripping Dekker off had all that information.
你是说  麦特认为某个ATF内部的人
Are you thinking that Matt thought
泄露了这些信息
that someone in the ATF leaked it?
我觉得他在调查
I think he was building a case.
他本可以借走戴克的那些钱
I mean, he could have borrowed the money off of Dekker,
把钱放在柜子里
planted it in the lockers
抓出那个泄露情报的人
to set up whoever was leaking that information.
如果是那样
If that were the case,
他会在报告里误报一些信息
he would have planted the misinformation in one of his reports.
看这个
Now look at this.
这个火奴鲁鲁动物园的入口就是放钱的地方
Here's an entry about the money drop at Honolulu Zoo.
计划明天上午九点把钱放在那里
Set to be dropped off at 9:00 a.m.,
十一点拿走
picked up at 11:00 a.m. tomorrow.
所以钱有两个小时的空挡被偷走
All right, that's a two hour window for the money to be stolen.
我们是对的
Yep, we were right.
麦特在给某个ATF的内鬼下套
Matt was setting someone up at the ATF.
肯尼迪
Kennedy.
他可能把戴克的交易信息
He could have been selling information to Tillman
卖给提勒曼
about Dekker's operation.
所以让麦特一直卧底  不展开行动
That's why he kept the case open and Matt undercover for so long.
他自己有好处
He was onto a good thing,
当然不想事情这么快了结
he didn't want it to end.
他让自己置身事外  却拿着大笔钱
Well, he keeps his hands clean, and he gets a cut of the profits.
当肯尼迪发现麦特识破了这些
And then when he found out that Matt was on to him,
就找了提勒曼的手下杀了他
Kennedy got one of Tillman's guys to kill him.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我要去完成麦特没完成的
I'm going to finish what Matt started.
你也来吗
You want to come?
行动
Let's do it.
听清楚了
All right, so listen up.
不管是谁  那人一打开柜子拿到钱就抓住他
Grab whoever picks up this money the second they open the locker.
我要这地方完全封锁起来
I want this entire place locked down.
每个出入口都有人把守
I want men on every exit,
周围每隔三十码就有两个人驻守
and I want two men every 30 yards around the perimeter.
开始行动
Let's go.
我不会这么做
I wouldn't have done it this way.
是吗
Yeah, you don't say?
麦格瑞特  我们应该等等
McGarrett, we should wait.
火奴鲁鲁动物园
等嫌疑人离开公园的时候你捉住他
Let your suspect exit the zoo, then you take him down.
那样我们就不用在这些人群之中
That way, we don't get into a firefight
开枪交战了
in the middle of all these civilians.
我想确保周围安全
I want to secure the perimeter.
好吗  他这次不会逃走了
Okay? He's not going to escape this time.
如果你上次能等特警来
He wouldn't have escaped last time
他上次就被抓住了
if you'd have just waited for SWAT.
如果我等特警来我可能已经死掉了
I could've been dead if I waited for SWAT.
或许是  但事情总有好坏两种方法
Maybe. But there's a right way and a wrong way to do things.
你不喜欢我  我知道了
You don't like me. All right? I get that.
但这次行动我是指挥
But I'm in command and control of this operation.
我是队长  明白吗
I'm also the team leader, okay?
所以你和你的团队
So you and your team,
你们要么和我联手  要么退出
you can come aboard with us or you can stand down.
你说了算
Whatever you say, uh...
少校
Commander.
科莫多巨蜥  夏威夷黄颈黑雁
没有发现
Nothing.
你记得把奶瓶给琼了吗
Did you remember to give Joan her bottle?
当然
Of course I did.
你在和麦克斯发消息是不是
You're texting Max right now, aren't you?
我没有
No, I'm not.
现在给琼喂奶
你真不会撒谎
You're a terrible liar.
有发现了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. I got something.
黑色连帽衫  径直前进
Black hoodie, straight ahead.
走得很快  直奔柜子
Moving fast, heading straight for the lockers.
不准动
Hold it right there.
怎么这么久
Took you long enough.
路上堵
Traffic.
不许动
Don't move a muscle.
为什么
Why?
看看这里  琳达
Take a look around, Linda.
看看你自己现在在哪里
Look at where you are.
看到这间屋子了吗
You see this room?
我们不是随便把你抓来的
You don't get to this room by accident.
都结束了
It's over.
我们知道你一直在把麦特的情报
We know you were feeding Matt's intel
交给你的这位男朋友
to your boyfriend here.
我们还知道  通过那些信息
And we know that with that information,
他和两个同伙
he and two of his associates
能够有组织地清除戴克的手下
were able to systematically rip off Dekker's crew.
昨天  这个人
Yesterday, this guy right here,
他将两个同伙爆头枪杀
he put two bullets in the back of their heads
以确保他们不会泄密
to make sure they kept quiet.
谁能保证
Now, who's to say
你拿到钱之后
he wouldn't have done the same thing to you
他会不会对你做出同样的事
after you collected that money?
麦特信任我们
Matt trusted us.
不  我们是他仅有的生机
No, we were his lifeline.
而你却背叛了他
And y-you betrayed him.
为了什么  钱吗
For what? Money?
不是
No.
我们只是不想进监狱
We just didn't want to go to jail.
闭嘴  琳达
Shut up, Linda!
你给我说清楚
You make me understand.
为什么要杀他
Why'd you have to kill him?
麦特几周前打来电话
Matt called a few weeks ago.
他想知道  谁有权限看到他的报告
He wanted to know who had access to his transcripts.
他怀疑报告被泄露了出去
He suspected that his reports had been compromised.
他查到我们只是时间的问题
It was only a matter of time until he traced that back to us.
对不起
I'm... sorry.
真的...
I'm...
对不起
so sorry.
问完了吗
You done here?
现在完事了
Now I am.
也许我该早点结束麦特的任务
Maybe I should've... pulled Matt out.
要是我能早点决定动手的话...
You know, if I-I'd just pushed the button sooner...
现在动手也不迟
What say we go push it now?
什么情况
What the hell is this?
我给你的录像里没有能定我罪的东西
There was nothing incriminating on that tape I gave you.
我的钱呢
Where's my money?
你的钱呢
Where's your money?
好消息是  我们找到了你的钱和枪
Good news is, we got your money and your guns.
坏消息是  我们拿走了你的钱和枪
Bad news is, we got your money and your guns.
艾莉森  你该看看这个
Allison, there's something you need to see.
给小麦特
爸爸
你好  小麦特
Hey, Matty.
我总是在想  你会长成什么样的男人
You know, I often dream about the kind of man you'll become...
有力量  有勇气  还有判别是非的能力
your strength and courage, your sense of right and wrong.
爸爸想要教给你的东西
There are so many things
实在是太多太多
a father wants to teach his son,
有时候需要言传身教
and sometimes you gotta teach by example.
通过接受这个任务
In accepting this assignment,
我希望能将这个世界变成一个
I hope I've helped make this world the kind of place
让你能够茁壮成长的地方
you deserve to grow up in.
儿子  人生中有很多艰难的抉择
Son, there's always hard choices in life,
牺牲在所难免
sacrifices that need to be made.
我想让你明白
I just want you to know Daddy made this one
爸爸因为爱你和妈妈才会做此选择
out of the love I have for you and your mother.
替我照顾好妈妈  孩子
You take care of her, kid.
你现在是家里的顶梁柱了
You're the man of the house now.
给你
There we go.
接着
Come on.
没有磕碰刮伤
Aw, no dings or scratches.
史蒂夫舅舅真称职
Looks like Uncle Steve did a good job.
有工作就要做好  仅此而已
I had a job to do, I did it. That's all.
承认吧  你也乐在其中
Oh, admit it. You had a little bit of fun.
我看出来了
I just saw you.
我是真的乐在其中
I-I definitely had a lot of fun.
她是个好孩子  玛丽
Yeah, she's a great kid, Mary.
谢谢你们
Aw, thank you.
下次再需要看孩子的话  我会联系你俩的
Well, next time I need a sitter I'll call on you two.
先让我说两句
Excuse me for a minute here, please.
没错  我们都出了力
Yes, we all contributed, but I was
但我得说  我是主力
primary on this one, I'd like to say.
好的  硬汉
Okay, tough guy.
跟叔叔们再见
Say goodbye to your uncles!
你要去哪  你不需要
Where-where you going? You don't... what?
你不用急着走
You don't need to rush off, do you?
再待一会吧
Just stick around for a bit.
我们刚结了案
Yeah, we just, uh, wrapped up this case.
接下来也没事了  我们可以
We got nothing on the board, so we could...
-一起吃个饭什么的  -没错
- Go out and get a bite to eat? - Right.
吃点儿豌豆糊
Got plenty of strained peas.
抱歉  我们要
Sorry, but we have
十分钟后要去图书馆参加婴儿故事角
Bouncy Baby Story Time at the library in ten minutes.
-跟史蒂夫舅舅再见  -再见
- So say, bye, uncle Steve! - Bye...
丹尼叔叔再见
Bye, Uncle Danny!
阿成叔叔再见
Bye, Uncle Chin!
好了
All right.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
再见
Bye, guys.
-再见  -再见
- Okay. See you. - Bye.
怎么了
What?
-真是个笨蛋  -没事
- You're such a softy. - Nothing.
-还好吗  -好极了
- You okay? - Never better.
查到了佐藤的位置
Got a location on Sato.
所有的监控录像
Full surveillance package...
地址  建筑草图  安保系统
address, structural blueprints, security system,
他手下的登陆信息
activity logs for his staff...
都在这了
Everything's there.
都是有用的
It's all good.
这都是你一个人做的
You, uh... do all that by yourself?
你想抢我们的饭碗吗
What, you trying to put us out of a job?
只是帮朋友的忙而已
No, just helping out a friend.
好吧
Okay.
对了  还有...
Oh, and, uh...
给你  多谢你借给我这个
Here. Thanks for the loaner.
这样吧
You know what?
-你留下它吧  -什么
- Why don't you keep it? - What?
拿着
Go ahead.
你需要工作
You need a job.
我们正缺人手
We need some help.
没错  相信我
Yeah. Trust me,
这个野蛮人需要帮忙的地方可不少
this, uh, animal, he needs all the help that he can get.
别考虑了
Don't think about it.
接受吧
Just say yes.
好吧
Okay.
我加入
Yes.
欢迎加入五零特遣队
Welcome to Five-O.